<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bruvik&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bruvik&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Anders Bruvik</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bruvik.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running pihole in a docker-container</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/pihole-in-a-docker-container-ipv6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/pihole-in-a-docker-container-ipv6/</guid>
      <description>Getting ipv6 to work with rpi, docker and pihole This is how I made pihole run in a docker container with ipv6 support.
Step one: Configure docker for ipv›6:
1 2 3 4 5  $ cat /etc/docker/daemon.json { &amp;#34;ipv6&amp;#34;: true, &amp;#34;fixed-cidr-v6&amp;#34;: &amp;lt;your-ipvc-cidr&amp;gt; }   then we need to create a ipv6 network for docker:
1  docker network create --ipv6 --driver bridge --subnet &amp;#34;fd01::/64&amp;#34; ipv6   restart docker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS3 conference 2020</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/cs3-conference-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/cs3-conference-2020/</guid>
      <description>CS3 conference 2020 I recently attended the CS3 conference in Copenhagen. I did a talk about our experiences from running ceph in production for almost 3 years, and here is a link to the slides from my talk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some useful GPG commands</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/useful-gpg-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/useful-gpg-commands/</guid>
      <description>Some useful gpg commands I recently ran into a problem with some gpg encrypted file, where the files were encrypted with another key than they were supposed to. Therefore I had to reencrypt them with another key. Every time I run into an unusual task with OpenGPG I find myself banging my head into a wall of useless documentation. Here’s some of the useful commands I found which let me resolve the issue:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS3 conference 2019</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/cs3-conference-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/cs3-conference-2019/</guid>
      <description>Summing up the CS3 conference 2019 This year started with a visit to Rome and the 5th edition of the CS3 (cloud services for synchronisation and sharing) - a yearly European conference that started as a workshop between Universities, National Research and Education networks and Research Centres in an attempt to exchange experiences in extending traditional storage technologies to the cloud.
This was my second visit to the conference, last time was two years ago, and I worked for the University of Oslo and visited primarily because of my interest in sync and sharing solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devopsdays Copenhagen 2019</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/devopsdays-copenhagen-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 10:25:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/devopsdays-copenhagen-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-from-devopsdays-copenhagen&#34;&gt;Summary from devopsdays Copenhagen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I visited Devopsdays Copenhagen for the second time (which also happened to be the second time the conference was arranged).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My old blog wasn&amp;rsquo;t updated in a long while, and I have planned to move from
Jekyll to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for a long while, so I finally set up everything.. I&amp;rsquo;m actually
not sure where the source for my old blog is, but if I find it, I might
republish some older stuff. And I have planned to publish more content soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devopsdays Oslo Books</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/devopsdays-oslo-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/devopsdays-oslo-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;books-mentioned-at-devopsdays-oslo-2017&#34;&gt;Books mentioned at devopsdays Oslo 2017&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of books mentioned during the talks at Devopsdays Oslo 2017.
I compiled a list of all the books mentioned. If you want to see the talks, you can find links to the recordings on the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.devopsdays.org/events/2017-oslo/welcome/&#34;&gt;Devopsdays website&lt;/a&gt; (the books
are listed by the speaker)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machinelearning resources from Devopsdays Oslo 2017</title>
      <link>https://bruvik.me/posts/machinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bruvik.me/posts/machinelearning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Devopsdays Oslo 2017, there was a discussion about machine learning at one of
the one of the openspace sessions. I made some notes from the session, and put
it into a gist that I shared on twitter. This is essentially that gist, so not
much editing here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>